You wanted to see me?
Yeah, have a seat.
ls it serious?
Wow. Andy's
a little scared.
Okay, right there.
Right there's the problem.
There have been reports
around the office
that you have been
talking baby talk.
Why would people
say that?
Well, l have it
on good authority that
you said the following.
Can you read that
back to me?
"Andy have
a boo-boo tummy."
Mmm-hmm.
Would you rather me say,
"Hey, guys,
my irritable bowel
syndrome is flaring up."
Okay.
"Crazy diarrhea
happening right now."
'Cause things can get
real adult real fast.
You are also on
record as saying,
"Wittle-ittle,
footie-wooties, num-nums,
"jammies, make boom-boom,
widiciwus, and Whode lsland."
Do l sometimes
replace Rs with Ws?
repeat a word to get
my point across?
Well, if l do,
Andy's sowwy.
You can't be a baby
in the office.
lt makes me look
like l hire babies.
Well, if we're
complaining,
a lot of people think
your Elvis voice
is annoying.
Okay. Who said that?
Just people.
For the record, l think
it's pretty fantastic.
Thank you.
Thank you a lot.
And for what it's worth,
l think your baby voice
is tops.
Tank you, Mr. Elvis.
You're welcome, baby.
Dr. Tuna M. D. , l have
some terrible news.
Wait, are you the patient
or the doctor?
The entire office
has come down
with a pernicious
case of the Mondays.
Wow. What do you put
our chances at?
0%.
Unless we perform
an immediate emergency
morale transplant, stat!
Sounds risky.
Don't worry.
There is a surefire cure.
Employee of the Month.
Every awesome place
l've worked had one.
Bear Stearns,
Lehman Brothers, AlG,
my summer at Enron.
Wow. That's not
such a bad idea.
Great.
Anything else?
Nope.
"Frankie's Dirty Joke
of the Day."
There's a bunch of those.
Keep.
There's a bunch
of sent emails that
just say "delivered."
Should l delete those?
l want to keep those
so l can see what l sent.
That's why you have
a sent mail folder.
Keep.
There's about
three news alerts
from Nip Slip.
For what?
Nip Slip.
Okay. l don't know
how those get on there.
Well. . .
Must be hackers.
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
Hey, what's up?
What if l told you
l had done the
worst thing ever?
Would you still want
to be my friend?
Did you murder someone?
Worse than murder.
Oh, my God.
Lurk much?
l miss Pam.
l think she's okay.
ls that what we're
going for now? "Okay"?
We used to go
for "pretty good."
Great.
Hey, how do you feel
about starting
an Employee of
the Month program?
Yeah. You know what,
that actually might
make me feel better.
l'm not in this for
the trophies, but. . .
You're not in it at all
'cause you can't be
Employee of the Month.
You're a manager.
Well, technically
l am a co-manager
and l barely have
any responsibilities.
All right. Yeah.
But l work hard,
l love this company,
and for those reasons
l think l would make a good
Employee of the Month.
lt would look bad. Sorry.
lt would look good
on my mantle.
Jim's talking to
Michael right now.
They totally
went for our idea!
Yeah ! Your idea.
My idea.
l just need Andy to
think it's his idea
so it won't get
traced back to me.
ln approximately six hours
Jim will get a phone call
from David Wallace.
He will be fired.
Hey, Pam, do you have
a sec to check over
this itinerary?
Looks great.
Did you really look it over?
Felt like maybe you didn't.
Okay.
The Michael Scott Foundation
is still in existence.
There you are.
l don't think we have
finished with my inbox.
What's "Scott's Tots"?
(LAUGHlNG)
Has it really
been 1 0 years?
(READlNG)
Michael, why did you
promise that?
To change lives.
No. Michael,
why would you
promise that?
You know. . .
Okay. l can't. . .
Call the school, cancel.
l can't go through with this.
We've already
rescheduled
seven times.
Michael, this is a terrible,
terrible thing you've done.
Well. . .
lt's terrible.
Just terrible.
And the longer
you put it off,
the worse it's gonna get.
l just. . .
l fell in love
with these kids,
and l didn't want to
see them fall victim
to the system.
So l made them
a promise.
l told them that
if they graduated
from high schooI,
l would pay for their
college education.
l have made some empty
promises in my life,
but hands down,
that was the
most generous.
Just tell me
it is going to be
okay, all right?
No!
l'm not a bad-news person.
l bring good news,
like when l
promised those kids
l'd pay for college.
(LAUGHlNG)
Okay. All right.
You have to tell them.
Would you come with me?
You know, like old times?
lnstead of. . .
l can print out
a new itinerary
with Pam's name on it.
lt's fine.
Erin, you're gonna go,
and you're gonna make sure
Michael tells the truth.
Oh, God. You know what?
Could this day get any worse?
Hey, Jimmy, what's up?
Not much.
Cool. Very cool.
l bet if you tried,
you could grow
the best beard of
anyone in this office.
Thanks, Dwight.
That laugh is
so infectious.
You're creeping me out.
l'm gonna go.
l didn't mean
any of those things
l just said.
And you can expect
the same thing from
everyone in this office
if you don't nip this whole
Employee of the Month
situation in the bud.
Make it about
the work.
Let me guess.
You think you
should get it.
This encompasses
all available data.
Hours, tardiness,
unconfirmed sick days,
participation.
Everyone has been assigned
a random number
for total fairness
and transparency.
Also, this should
be accompanied by
a monetary prize.
Well, in an
ideal world. . .
ln an ideal world
l would have
all 1 0 fingers
on my left hand,
so my right hand
could just be
a fist for punching.
Okay. lf it's all
the same to you,
l'm just gonna take
away survival skills
and self-defense.
l'm gonna run this
by Toby and Accounting
and have them
assemble the data.
lt's okay,
l'll do it.
MlKELA: Mr. Scott?
Hey! Mikela Lasker!
How are you?
l'm good.
Good to see you.
Where's your saxophone?
lt's in the music room,
Mr. Scott.
Eighth-grade graduation,
she gave a rendition
of When the Saints Go
Marching In that would
blow your freaking mind.
Wow.
Well, you didn't
even hear it.
Everyone's so excited
that you're here today.
Oh, good.
Now,
l know you probably
want to see everyone,
but l was wondering
if l could ask you
some questions first.
Sure.
You're famous.
l'm sure you remember
this place.
Oh, yeah.
Do you want to go in?
No, not at all.
Nope. Come on.
You know what? You know,
l shouldn't go in there.
l'm pretty busy.
l shouldn't. . .
We just want
to say thanks.
ALL: Mr. Scott!
Mr. Scott! Mr. Scott!
Mr. Scott!
Mr. Scott,
l know you're a busy man
and your schedule
moves around a lot,
but for all your generosity
through the years, your tots,
who are ready
to graduate,
thought it was
time to give you
a proper thank you.
(STUDENTS EXCLAlMlNG)
(SlNGlNG) Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
You came into our lives
and made a promise
That made us honest
Made us realize
We don't need to compromise
'Cause we can have it all
'Cause you made it possible
For us to achieve
the improbabIe
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
Wow!
Hey. So Jim thought
it would be ideal. . .
Hey.
. . .if we all pitched in. . .
So, Jim thought
it would be ideal
if we all pitched in a 20
for this whole Employee
of the Month thing.
Jim said that?
He thought you were doing
an incredible job last month.
Jim said that?
You seem surprised.
No, no, that makes
total sense.
Hey, buddy.
So everyone. . .
Five minutes
ahead of schedule.
Right on schedule.
Politicians are
always coming around,
telling us they're
gonna fix our schools,
promising this and that.
But you, Mr. Scott,
you are actually doing it!
You have taught these kids,
with hard work,
that anything is possible.
You are a dream maker,
and l thank you.
l thank you. l thank you,
l thank you, l thank you.
There were a lot of
times over the years
where l was pressured
to get into the drug game.
But l always thought back
to my guardian angel
and the gift
that you gave me.
So l just want to thank you
for giving me the opportunity
to go to college,
educate myself,
and become
the next President Obama.
Oh, God.
Okay, ladies and
gentlemen, welcome.
l know you're all very
excited, but no matter
who gets this,
l just want to say
that you guys are all
Employees of the Month
in my eyes.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
And the winner is
employee number nine,
and that is. . .
Number nine,
number nine, Jim Halpert.
ANGELA: What?
KEVlN: What?
Are you kidding me?
Oh, no.
Okay, wait.
l was not. . .
l did not get. . .
"l did not. . .
That was not. . .
"How come not. . ."
Guys, listen.
This was anonymous,
all right?
There's no way
l could have
given it to myself,
because l didn't even know
who was on here.
l just gave it to
the employee with the
highest overall score.
To my tally,
you just won back
your own parking spot,
a vacation day,
and a nice tidy quarter
of $1 ,000 from all of us.
Will everybody just
stop for a second?
'Cause obviously l'm
not taking any of it.
A mistake has been made
and we'll figure it out.
Second of all,
there was no cash prize.
Yes!
Dwight?
Yeah, you said,
"ln an ideal world,
there would be
a cash prize."
lsn't that
what you said?
No, Dwight, l meant,
yes, in a perfect world,
someone would get money,
but not. . .
Yeah, but,
in your perfect world,
only you get money.
KEVlN: Yeah, that's. . .
ANGELA: Don't do this. . .
DWlGHT: l know,
all right?
Don't do. . .
Let's put your hands together
and give a warm welcome
for the man of the hour,
Mr. Michael Scott.
(WHOOPlNG)
Thank you.
All right. Wow.
l am never going
to forget today.
Not a chance.
l don't think l could
ever give back to you
what you have given me today.
Who here's done
something stupid
in their lives?
Like skipped out
on study hall
or mix up the difference
between A gym and B gym,
that sort of thing?
Show of hands.
Anybody? Yes,
a bunch of you. Okay.
Well, me, too.
l've done something stupid,
which l would like to share.
Um. . .
(SCHOOL BELL RlNGlNG)
Should we go?
No, no, we're okay.
lt's a double period.
All right.
l came here today because
l promised you tuition,
and tuition is
very valuable.
But you know
what's invaluable?
ls intuition.
You know what that is?
That is the ability to
know when something is
about to happen.
Does anybody out there
have intuition?
Know what's gonna
happen next?
Nobody? Okay.
You're gonna
make me say it.
All right.
l am so proud
of all of you.
Derrick and Lefervre
and Ben and Ayana
and Mikela and Nikki
and Jason and. . .
l'm sorry, okay,
l'm sort of
spacing your name.
l'm Zion.
l'm Mikela's
younger brother.
Well, Zion,
l am not going to be
paying for your tuition.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Which brings me
to my main point,
and that is that l
will not be able to pay
for anybody's tuition.
l'm so, so sorry.
GlRL: What?
BOY: You're kidding.
Excuse me?
(CLAMORlNG)
l'm sorry.
Explain yourself, sir!
l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
l'm so sorry.
You lied to us.
Yep. l lied to myself, too.
l'm not a millionaire.
l thought l would be
by the time l was 30,
but l wasn't even close,
and then l thought maybe
by the time l was 40,
but by 40
l had less money
than when l was 30.
Maybe by my 50s,
l don't know.
l wanted to pay
for your education.
l really did.
lt was my dream.
Some people have evil dreams,
some people have
selfish dreams,
or wet dreams.
My dream was in
the right place.
You owe this to us.
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
Now, l can't pay
for your college,
but you don't
have to go to class
to be in class.
Online courses
are a viable option
to a traditional
college experience,
and the best way to
access those courses
is with your own
personal laptop,
which is
rendered useless
without batteries,
and l have one
for each of you.
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
Hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on, hold on.
They're lithium.
Look, there was
a big mistake, obviously,
so l will fix it. Okay?
This was
your idea anyway.
Correction.
lt was my idea.
Okay.
My idea.
Guys, l'm starting to think
Pam's not even pregnant.
Okay, for the record,
l am pregnant,
and obviously
there's been some
kind of a mistake,
so why doesn't Jim just
pick the next highest
score on the list
and we'll move on.
Yeah, okay.
That's fair.
Excellent idea, Pam.
Thank you.
That would be
employee number three,
which is. . .
Son of a bitch !
Pam Halpert.
ALL: What?
How is that possible?
No offense, Pam,
but how the hell
is that possible?
There must be
some reasonable
explanation for this.
Wait, come on.
l didn't miss a day,
l came in early,
l stayed late,
and l doubled my
sales last month.
Oh, really?
From what?
Two to four?
Yep.
Guys, this isn't some
elaborate scam, okay?
Hi, l have an order
here for a custom cake.
Jim Halpert.
Okay. That is me,
but l didn't order
the cake.
Look who it is.
(ALL EXCLAlMlNG)
(ANGELA READlNG)
DWlGHT:
He knew all along.
KELLY: l'm gonna
have some cake.
STEPHANlE:
David Wallace's office.
This is Kevin Malone.
ls David there?
No, he's in his
weekIy staff meeting.
Can l take a message?
Tell him l'm mad at Jim
'cause he's asking us
to give money to Pam.
This is Stanley Hudson.
Jim Halpert is a menace.
lt's Toby Flenderson.
Listen, things are getting
really bad down here.
Hey, Mr. Scott.
Erin, can you
give us a second?
That was messed up
what you did.
Yeah, yeah,
l know. l know.
l know, l'm sorry.
Who does something
like that?
Who promises that
to a bunch of kids
and then just doesn't
come through like that?
What can l do?
You could pay
for my college.
l can give you
an extra laptop battery.
Not everyone took one.
(SlGHS)
How about this?
lf you can find a way
to pay for your tuition,
let me buy your books, okay?
They're expensive.
Yeah, well, l owe you
that at least, right?
lt's about $1 ,000.
(EXHALES) Really? Wow.
That's over $200 a year.
No, $1 ,000 each year.
For. . . Okay. Okay.
Here's what l'm gonna do.
l'm gonna write four checks
for $1 ,000 each.
l'm going to date them
one year apart.
Now, you are to use
one check a year,
and please call me
before you cash the check,
'cause l've got monies
to move around.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay?
Make it out
to my Aunt Rosa.
That's a lot of zeroes.
This is Jim.
DAVID: Jim, what the hell
is happening there?
Hey, David.
Yes?
So, there was a little bit
of a miscommunication
here today.
lt's been a little wild,
but l am on it.
Just so l understand,
you started
EmpIoyee of the Month,
give it to yourseIf,
then peopIe compIain,
so you give it
to your wife?
No.
Am I missing something?
l really don't know
how it happened, David.
l know how it happened.
DAVID: Jim, I bumped you up
because I thought you couId
make my Iife easier.
If you can't do that,
we're gonna have
a separate discussion.
JIM: AII right,
it wiII not happen again.
I promise.
I am sorry.
I am taking
this out on you.
No.
But things have
been crazy here.
You know
I think you're doing
a great job, right?
What? No.
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay. (CHUCKLES)
We still on for
dinner this weekend?
What?
Yes.
Okay. See you.
You're kidding me!
Damn it!
(SlNGlNG) Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
Please stop.
Fifteen lives.
l destroyed
1 5 young lives today.
No.
Yes.
No, there's
financial aid.
They could join
the Army or the Navy.
Maybe. . .
You're, what, like, 1 2?
The principal
told me that
90% of Scott's Tots are
on track to graduate,
and that's 35% higher
than the rest of the school,
so l think that
if you hadn't
made that promise,
a lot of them
would have dropped out,
which is something to
think about, l think.
l think you're
doing a great job.
Really?
What do you want
from this job,
provided the company
doesn't go out of business?
Well, l've always wondered
what it might be like to be
an accountant.
Really?
Yes, but l'm
terrible at math.
Well, you know,
when l hired Kevin,
he was actually applying
for a job in the warehouse.
Seriously?
Yeah.
l just sort of had
a feeling about him.
Have a feeling
about you, too.
(SlNGlNG) Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
Hey, Mr. Scott,
what you gonna do
What you gonna do
Make our dreams come true
Yeah !
JlM: See you
tomorrow, Dwight.
Apparently.
How's it going?
Good day?
Not now, temp.
Okay. So, listen,
l know about your
diabolical plan.
What? Diabolical plan?
l wouldn't even know
how to begin. . .
l found a copy of it
in the copier tray.
So what do you want?
l want the same thing
you want.
l want to take
Jim Halpert down.
l want in.